# 山东·济南
Jinan, Shandong
# 我又在济南了
I’m in Jinan again
# 这次来济南呢 是为了把自己的颌垫去掉
To take off my occlusal guards
# 颌垫去掉之后 当然要吃点好的了
Of course I’m going to eat delicious food after taking it off
# 昨天我有个朋友发了很多的美食图片
My friend posted lots of food pictures yesterday
# 里面最吸引我的 最让我觉得馋的不是肉
I was not interested in meat the most,
# 而是烧饼
But Shaobing
# 想想自己也是很长时间没有吃到烧饼火烧这些东西了
Come to think of it, I haven’t had Shaobing or Huoshao in a very long time
# 今天中午去买点
We are going to get some for lunch
# 如果觉得好吃 就再给她捎一点回去
I will take some for her if it is delicious
# 店的门口已经坐了几桌来吃饭的人了
There are already some people coming to have lunch sitting by the front door
# 进去看看吧
Let’s take a look inside
# （菜单）
The menu
# 看我后面 这边来买牛肉烧饼的人好多
Look behind me, there are a lot of people coming here to buy beef Shaobing
# 关键是 现在还不到十一点 人就这么多了
The point is, there are already so many people here before 11 am
# 在哪儿交钱
Where to pay?
# 我要一个烧饼夹牛肉 和一碗牛肉汤
I want a beef Shaobing and a bowl of beef soup
# 在这儿吃？ 对
Dine in? -Yes.
# 18块钱
18 yuan
# 这个牛肉 闻着就是挺香的
The beef smells very fragrant
# （阿姨说一天得卖3锅牛肉）
(Auntie said they sell 3 pots of beef every day)
# （阿姨说闻着就特别香）
(She says it smells very fragrant)
# 谢谢
Thank you
# 这是小碗的牛肉汤（10元）
This is the small bowl of beef soup (10 yuan)
# 这个碗都是这么大的！
Look how large the "small bowl" is!
# 牛肉烧饼也来了（8元）
Beef shaobing is here as well (8 yuan)
# 看这个头不小吧
Look at the size of this
# 这一面全是芝麻 量多让人感动
This side is packed with sesame seeds, very impressive!
# 它肯定是怕我觉得它不够香
They must fear that I find it not fragrant enough.
# 我们打开烧饼 看一看里面的牛肉
Let’s open the Shaobing, and take a look at the beef inside
# 哇
Wow
# 这个牛肉切的特别细
The beef is finely chopped
# 我感觉是瘦肉多 肥肉少
I think there is more lean meat than fat
# 几乎看不到肥肉
Almost no fat
# 来一口吧
Take a bite
# 好香阿
So fragrant
# 这个烧饼是咸香味的 芝麻的味道特浓郁
The Shaobing is savory and fragrant, with a deep sesame flavor
# 我用手撕一下它的外壳
Let me tear its shell with my hands
# 看看刚烤的烧饼是多么的酥脆
so that you know how crispy the freshly baked Shaobing is
# 芝麻都掉了好多
Many sesames dropped
# 里面是分层的
It’s layered inside
# 因为加了足够的芝麻所以即使没有肉也很香
Because there is plenty of sesame, it tastes delicious even without meat
# 透过窗户也能看到 它这个牛肉原来是放在汤里的
You can see it through the window. The beef was in the soup
# 现要呢 就是现捞出来 现剁出来
It is taken out and chopped by order
# 就是切成这种小细末
Just chopped into these small pieces
# 夹在里面
Folded into the Shaobing
# 肉多到就是感觉无从下口
There is so much meat that I don’t know where to start
# 我看很多人都是直接来买牛肉
I see many people come directly to buy beef
# 有的人也是直接来买烧饼
Others for the Shaobing
# 烧饼呢 一个人都能买四五个（这种都是带走的）
Four or five Shaobing per person (all takeout)
# 这都是比较正常的
Which is common
# 它这个牛肉汤就会比较清淡
Its beef soup is lightly seasoned
# 这家小店离市区很远 但是很多人都是专门开车过来吃
This small restaurant is very far away from the city, but many people drive here to eat
# 这边的火烧还有牛肉 主要就是价格比较合适
Shaobing and beef are cost-effective
# 一个呢 就是让你吃得饱饱的 味道也还不错
It feeds you well with great taste
# 在这边吃着饭 还能听到他们时不时传来的爽朗的笑声
You can hear their unrestrained laughter while eating here
# 来 我们看一下火烧和牛肉 制作的场景
Let’s check out how they make Shaobing and beef
# 大哥
# 我看你这边找的大部分都是娘子军
Mister, I noticed that most of your workers are female
# 一进来一看
# 全是女的
I get inside and take a look, all ladies
# 阿姨 这边早上起来是几点开门
Ms., when does the restaurant open in the morning?
# 早上起来6点 6点开门
6 am
# 您刚才说 一早上的顾客怎么了
What did you just say about customers in the morning?
# 人不断 都是来吃火烧的
They all come for Shaobing
# 大姨 这个还得称一下吗
Auntie, do you have to weigh this?
# 每一个大约是多重
What’s the weight of each one?
# 一两六 不超过一两六
1.6 liang, no more than 1.6 liang(around 80 grams)
# 哦 是蘸了水
Oh, after dipping it in water
# 蘸了水 才能把芝麻粘住
Dip it in water so that the sesame seeds can stick
# 现在已经开始上人了 看我后面 这边有
Customers are coming
# 1 2 3 4 5 6 7
One, two, three, four, five, six, seven.
# 有七个人在忙碌
Seven people are busy making food
# 就先不打扰他们了 我去买点火烧带走
I won’t bother them for now. I will get some Shaobing for takeout
# 这是我买的火烧
These are the Shaobing that I bought
# 待会回去分一下
I'll go back and share them later
# 她现在应该是上班的时候
She should be at work right now
# 还没有理我 回复我消息
Still haven't reply to my messages yet
# 关  注
# 雪 鱼  探 店
Subscribe
Xue yu